talkwithstranger.com 2019-04-25

# TalkWithStrangers Privacy Policy - Free Random Chat Rooms With Strangers | Free Online Chat

Read our Privacy Policy & Terms of Use of Our Website

##  At TalkWithStanger.com and/or TalkWithStanger, TalkToStrangers (“TalkWithStranger”, “Website”, “we”, “our”, or “us”), we are committed to protecting the information provided to us by our users, including but not limited to visitors to our website, users and customers (“users” or “you”). It is our policy to respect the privacy of individuals and the confidentiality of information provided by our users. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) outlines how we collect, disclose, use, store and handle personal information provided by our users. 

Alternatively, if you don't find an answer to what you are looking for please  contact us. 

Last Updated: 21st Feb 2019 

###  **Preamble**

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website. 

###  **Terms & Conditions Usage of our Chat Site **

By using the TalkWithStranger Web site, and/or related products and/or services ("TalkWithStranger", provided by ), you agree to the following terms: **Do not use TalkWithStranger if you are under 13.** Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 13 ("Children"). We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If you are under 18, use it only with a parent/guardian's permission. Do not transmit nudity, sexually harass anyone, publicize other peoples' private information, make statements that defame or libel anyone, violate intellectual property rights, use automated programs to start chats, or behave in any other inappropriate or illegal way on TalkWithStranger. Understand that human behavior is fundamentally uncontrollable, that the people you encounter on TalkWithStranger may not behave appropriately, and that they are solely responsible for their own behavior. Use TalkWithStranger at your own peril. Disconnect if anyone makes you feel uncomfortable. You may be denied access to TalkWithStranger for inappropriate behavior, or for any other reason. TalkWithStranger IS PROVIDED AS IS, AND TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT ALLOWED BY APPLICABLE LAW, IT IS PROVIDED WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, NOT EVEN A WARRANTY OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT ALLOWED BY APPLICABLE LAW, THE PROVIDER OF TalkWithStranger, AND ANY OTHER PERSON OR ENTITY ASSOCIATED WITH TalkWithStranger'S OPERATION, SHALL NOT BE HELD LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT OR INDIRECT DAMAGES ARISING FROM THE USE OF TalkWithStranger, OR ANY OTHER DAMAGES RELATED TO TalkWithStranger OF ANY KIND WHATSOEVER. 

###  **Parental Control Softwares**

Parental control protections (such as computer hardware, software, or filtering services) are commercially available that may assist you in limiting access to material that is harmful to minors. If you are interested in learning more about these protections, information is available at **[List of Parental Control Softwares](http://www.techradar.com/news/the-best-free-parental-control-software "Parental control softwares to block chat sites") ** as well as a number of other Internet sites that provide information on this form of protection. 

###  **What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website or app?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address or other details to help you with your experience. At TalkWithStranger, we collect information which are essential for providing a better and more efficient chatting experience to you and other users of their Website. Information we may collect includes the login information you provide us with each time you open an account on our Website (including but not limited to name, contact details, phone number, email, username and password), any information which you might fill up on the Website by subscribing to any of the services offered on the site, your correct date of birth, and any information provided to us by means of correspondence (including but not limited to email, telephone or fax)(together, “Personal Information”). In case you do not wish disclose any such Personal Information, please do not set up an account on our website, or directly provide us with any Personal Information though any method (including but not limited to the methods listed above) of communication. By registering on our Website, you agree to provide us with accurate, complete and up-to-date information. 

###  **How long we keep your personal information?**

We retain your personal information for as long as is necessary to provide the services to you and others, and to comply with our legal obligations. If you no longer want us to use your personal information or to provide you with the TalkToStranger services, you can request that we erase your personal information and close your TalkWithStanger account. Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information we will retain information from deleted accounts as necessary for our legitimate business interests, to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the terms of service and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

###  **How to opt out of your information or subscription?**

If you dont want to use TWS services and want to opt out of our site. There are multiple ways for you to do this. We have explained some of them below: 

* Goto your profile settings page, and disable all email notifications as well as opt out for any subscription based services.
* Goto the contact us page of TWS, Email us with your account ID, email and put in the subject "Opt out of "Name of the Product" . We should be happy to opt out your from our site products wherever we send you notifications.

###  **If you’re a user or visitor in the European Economic Area these rights also apply to you:**

For the purposes of applicable EU data protection law (including the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), we are a ‘data controller’ of your personal information. 

###  **How you can access your personal information?**

You are also entitled to ask us to port your personal information (i.e. to transfer in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, to you), to erase it, or restrict its processing. You also have rights to object to some processing that is based on our legitimate interests, such as profiling that we perform for the purposes of direct marketing, and, where we have asked for your consent to process your data, to withdraw this consent as more fully described below. These rights are limited in some situations – for example, we can demonstrate that we have a legal requirement to process your personal information. In some instances, this means that we may retain some data even if you withdraw your consent. Where we require your personal information to comply with legal or contractual obligations, then provision of such data is mandatory: if such data is not provided, then we will not be able to manage our contractual relationship with you, or to meet obligations placed on us. In all other cases, provision of requested personal information is optional. If you have unresolved concerns you also have the right to complain to data protection authorities. The relevant data protection authority will be the data protection authority of the country: (i) of your habitual residence; (ii) of your place of work; or (iii) in which you consider the alleged infringement has occurred. 

###  **Where do we use your information (if needed)?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. Third-party links We do not include or offer third-party products or services on our website. Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en We use Google Ad Exchange Advertising on our website through partner ship with Sortable. Google might associate the ads you see on our website with your Google account so that you can see personalized Ads (Interest based Ads) Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy. 

###  **Why do we collect information?**

At TalkWithStranger, we need your Information to provide users a seamless chatting experience on our website, and to efficiently manage any enquiries, requests or complaints that you may have, or to notify you of any promotions, offers or updates that we may have. We may disclose your Information to our subcontractors, subsidiaries, affiliates or third party advertisers, service providers (including those hosting and managing our Website, providing customer service, marketing and advertising and other related services), and sponsors who administer our promotions. Information can be used to manage and administer coupons or contests, for promotions or surveys, to conduct research and analysis, improve TalkWithStranger’s monitoring process, to prevent fraudulent transactions, or to monitor against theft and otherwise protect users, guests or our Website. 

###  **If I have a problem, how can I contact TWS support?**

You can certainly go to our contact page and contact us at any time when you have an issue. We are here to help you resolve your problems and love to hear from you. Feel free to give us new suggestions or if you have any query please  contact us. 

###  **Do we collect cookies?**

We use cookies to: 

  * Understand and save user's preferences for future visits. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If users disable cookies in their browser: If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It will turn off some of the features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. However, you can still chat, just your last nickname won't be saved. 
  * We fully comply our site with EU cookie law and by using TWS, you give us permission to store cookies on your machine, see more info [here](https://www.cookielaw.org/the-cookie-law/)

###  **Your Personal Information?**

We never ask our users to share their personal information with us and we don't recommend them to share with others on the website. This is why we have also disabled URLs sharing in the random chat. We (TWS) will not be responsible for any information you share with other users . As we don't collect any personal information from our users. By using talkwithstranger, you are agreeing to all the terms and condition of our website. 

###  **Information you make public or give to others**

If you make your personal information available to other people, we can’t control or accept responsibility for the way they will use or manage that data. There are lots of ways that you can find yourself providing information to other people, like when you post a public message on a forum thread, share information via social media, or make contact with another user (such as a third party Author) whether via our Sites or directly via email. Before making your information publicly available or giving your information to anyone else, think carefully. If giving information to another user via our Sites, ask them how they will handle your information. If you’re sharing information via another website, check the privacy policy for that site to understand its information management practices as this privacy policy will not apply. 

###  **How we collect personal information?**

We collect personal information directly when you provide it to us, automatically as you navigate through the Sites, or through other people when you use services associated with the Sites. We collect your personal information when you provide it to us when you complete membership registration and or provide items or services on our Sites, subscribe to a newsletter, email list, submit feedback, enter a contest, fill out a survey, or send us a communication. 

###  **Use of Logs?**

We may collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Service ("Log Data"). This Log Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics. However, this is by no means assures that our chat logs are retrievable on our servers. Our website remains anonymous and private, and only the information you enter or tell to your chat partner is what you send and is visible to your chat partner only. Everything else stays private throughout your chat session. Once the chat is exited, there is no way for users to retrieve it back. In addition, we may use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and analyze this type of information in order to increase our Service's functionality. These third party service providers have their own privacy policies addressing how they use such information. 

###  **Advertisement and associated information collected**

We may use non-google 3rd party advertising networks and other content recommendation software to show interest based advertisements. This might give those ad networks and advertisers to collect some basic information about the users on our site. They will not be able to uniquely identify anyone, information such has your IP, browser, mobile model etc . These information are solely to be used for targeted advertisement and not for uniquely identifying any individual user. Similarly our tracking software such as Google Analytics collects similar information to further give us analysis of our website performance so we can give our users an excellent User Experience. When you visit our Sites, there’s certain information that’s recorded which is generally anonymous information and does not reveal your identity. If you’re logged into your account some of this information could be associated with your account. We’re talking about the following kinds of details: 

  1. your IP address or proxy server IP address’; 
  2. the domain name you requested;’; 
  3. the name of your internet service provider is sometimes captured depending on the configuration of your ISP connection; 
  4. the date and time of your visit to the website; 
  5. the length of your session; 
  6. the file URL you look at and information relating to it; 
  7. the website which referred you to our Sites; and 
  8. the pages which you have accessed;; 
  9. the number of times you access our site within any month; 

###  **Our Aim**

  * TWS aim is to provide 100% anonymous chat and discussion experience and that we NEVER IDENTIFY any user directly and nor we sell user's information to advertisers. We never ask you to share your personal info like kik, snapchat, whatsapp, instagram or any detail on our platform. If you do share such things then it is no longer our responsbility to control that information as YOU HAVE THE SUPREME CONTROL over what you can share on our platform. 
  * our site is focused on user-generated content, so sometimes it can get hard to control user's actions and behaviour, but we r constantly working hard to have active moderation, flagging and content reviews and have checks in place to ensure a friendly and safe eco-system for all everyone. 

###  **Rules & Policies of TWS Community**

  * TWS is a family friendly site, and we strictly prohibit any 18+ or adult content on our site. 
  * Asking, Posting or swapping picture and all related to Adult, Nude and same stuffs are not acceptable and will take serious actions against the specified user. 
  * Using Adult keywords in a Topic or Post or as a Username, AND also Adult Pictures as profile picture or whatever at the same level are not acceptable.
  * Making topics with inappropriate contents equals warning and topic deleting.
  * Junk Posts or topics, and also Spamming in anyway would face with serious actions at the first place. 
  * If there's a business talk with strangers, try to make your desired topic and explain it therein, spamming it in private chats or disturbing people equals banning.
  * Never Share your real informations such as real phone number, email address or skype number and id. there's no responsibility from our side if every thing happens after your sharing at the very first stage.
  * Try not to flag some one for no reason, it causes misunderstandings and warnings if there was no exact reason for that.
  * Fake Users will get banned after warnings, please avoid making fake accounts.
  * Promoting or linking sites about online dating, making friends or money making, and also scamming sites for grabbing users personal infos is totally unacceptable.
  * Make sure you don't make the website unusable with excessively repeated posting of topics or links or images in both topics and public chat sections for other users. Such actions will face serious actions.
  * You can curse, but you can't be very offensive towards a fellow user. You CANNOT insult the parents or culture of the user, you cannot make the user feel uncomfortable in any way. TWS wants a friendly environment for all its users.
  * Public chatroom always welcomes healthy discussions, but then that discussion shouldn't turn into a group fight. Opinions of people always differ, you should respect them. TWS supports group messaging you can use that facility if you want to argue/fight on your opinion with a specific set of people. 
  * You have your Freedom of speech at the same time the other users have their Right to dignity. Your Right to free speech is not to impede their Right to dignity. In case your actions are degrading other users or making their experience undesirable, necessary actions will be taken against you.

For further details please [visit](https://chatrooms.talkwithstranger.com/topic/2616/how-to-rules-and-features-of-the-community-tws-welcome-topic/7). 

###  **Business Transition**

In the event that we go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, we reserve the right to transfer or assign the information we have collected from our users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. We will post a notice on the Site of any such change in ownership or control of the personal information we may have prior to such transfer. 

###  **Data Security**

TalkWithStranger has commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to ensure the security of our systems and protect personal information from misuse, loss and unauthorized access. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to TalkWithStranger and you do so at your own risk. If TalkWithStranger learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. TalkWithStranger may post a notice on the TalkWithStranger Site or through the TalkWithStranger Service if a security breach occurs. 

###  **User's control on info**

We have multiple ways through which users can control what they share or if think something is wrong they can report as well.Our website has various filtering, blacking and reporting features to avoid spammers and bullies. You can use those features to report any bad activity on the site. On our chatroom community platform we also have privacy settings where users can restrict other people from sending messages to them or follow them online. 

###  **Is TWS (TalkWithStranger) is secure?**

Yes, our website is on HTTPS which ensures 100% safe and secure experience for all the users on the website. 

###  **Does any third party has access to it?**

Yes, as stated in the  **"Where do we use your information (if needed)?"** , we use Google and the third party advertisers to show ads and they may store cookies and some device information to provide targeted advertisement to our users. 

###  **Compliance with the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) Code of Conduct**

  * A conspicuous hyper-link to an NAI-approved Opt-Out mechanism for Interest-Based Advertising, such as - [here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/)
  * A clear statement to the fact that data may be collected for the purpose of Interest-Based Advertising on the property. 
  * A description of the types of data that is collected from users for the purpose of Interest-Based Advertising. 
  * An explanation of the purposes for which the collected data will be transferred to third-parties. 

###  **Changes to Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be revised periodically. However, we will not use your Personal Information in a way that is materially different than the uses described in this Policy without giving you an opportunity to opt-out of such differing uses. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. Your continued use of the TalkWithStranger Site and TalkWithStranger Service constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any amendments.
